welcome to our review of the year it's
nearly New Year so we're going to look
back over the films that you put out on
the channel and try and kind of see
whether there's a narrative two of them
or maybe we can impose a narrative on it
and I think there is I mean I've worked
out sort of what the main films were
that we put out like what was most
viewed we're going to play some clips
from then we're going to talk about a
little bit of the kind of backstory
behind some of the films and try and see
where where what the trajectory of the
channel has been over the last year and
maybe where we're going next
yes since the beginning of the channel
we very much felt that we're sort of
following an unfolding narrative sort of
following whatever feels most alive in
the culture and trying to keep that sort
of generative quality of exploration
yeah so looking back across the year has
been quite an interesting exercise and
seeing okay is there a narrative that
binds everything together that we've
been covering there's often as often we
are I think responding to what feels
alive and going on intuition as well as
intellect but in the moment things
happen very fast in culture and looking
back on it I think there are a few
threads we've been covering so we've
been covering from the beginning of the
channel the sense of how do we have a
real conversation that takes us
somewhere new so a lot of the content
we've had is in some way related to that
from the intellectual dark web to the
science psychology of polarization
collective intelligence so there's that
thread and I think there's also the
thread of the shadows in culture what
are the aspects that of what's happening
culturally and individually that we need
to own and look at and bring out so
that's been another key theme not
wanting to give away too much about
what's coming up later but let's start
in January with the Gillette advert and
we were actually out in Thailand at the
time we're doing a working holiday in
Thailand and then the Gillette ad came
out and there was this huge kind of up
swirl of like it was a major cultural
moment at the time so I guess I'm gonna
frame this film that we're doing now
it's gonna be we've done a whole series
called men and women after me - based on
the premise that if the cultural
conversation right now looks like a
dysfunctional relationship and I think
it does what does a functional
relationship look like and just for
anyone who's been living under a stone
for the last couple of days and hasn't
seen this I mean the amount of you
it's had it was up to about nine million
views in a very short space of time at
two days hugely polarized reactions it
was running about 10 to 1 dislikes to
light ratio it's now up to about 4 to 1
let's start by talking about the film
itself yes because it was done by a very
high-profile director Kim Gehrig so a
female director who did a very
well-received and very successful
campaign called this girl can and we're
going to play a little clip from that
now and we'll just sort of then unpack
the differences and what it says about
the cultural context I'm the hottest
wave jockey stop me now
this girl can't I think is a great
campaign it actually by death by pretty
much any definition was a great campaign
it took a real need and a real issue
which is women feeling like they didn't
want to exercise because they didn't
feel confident their bodies they felt
people were watching them I have a lot
of female friends who told me about this
about the kind of feeling especially
like in the freeway section of the gym
like I really want to go in there so it
took that need he did a great campaign
around it and they go something like
well according to an award entry they
did you know 1.6 million women doing
exercise attributable to some way in
that to that campaign which is great so
really different response to the
Gillette ad and I think part of that is
because so this girl can everything in
there is aspirational is this girl can
do this she can do this she can do this
it's you know kind of don't hold me down
great very empowering nothing wrong with
that did you let ad if it's this girl
can it's very much these men should
completely different energy to it and
you mentioned catch-22 which is the kind
of feeling that I take away from the
Gillette ad the ad coming out and then
the reaction afterwards in the backlash
in the backlash against the backlash and
what was really fascinating is there's
this narrative in the culture certainly
it's a progressive culture that men need
to be more emotionally honest they need
to need to speak out more let me to say
what they're seeing
silence killing men which we like that
part that's true that there's some real
truth in that we run men's retreats
where we provide spaces for men to be
emotionally honest and it's
transformative like being an immense
group speaking with your friends about
what's going on they're all valuable
skills that that we as men need to learn
but then on the flip side of that
there's this sort of narrative of when
men men on mass spoke out said we don't
like this to your left add it demeans us
it's hectoring we don't need to be told
how to behave by a massive corporation
all of these responses what you saw from
progressive suppose had progressive
people is male fragility our look at you
get over yourselves men being shut down
so this is the catch-22
in the culture right now is men you need
to be open you need to share yourselves
more and then when you do you're jumped
on and I saw progressive friends who in
any other context would not be saying a
man up don't complain
stop being fragile we're saying exactly
that and it's it the performative
contradiction is what boggles me and
that catch-22 is what we see with a lot
of men you come to the men's retreat is
this sense of and damned if I do and I'm
damned if I don't I'm damned if I'm
silent and don't say what I'm saying
what I'm thinking and if I do say what
I'm thinking and that happens in
relationships with your with your
partner when we play the clip from
brandy Brown where she said as a as a
woman be honest with yourself when your
partner shares with you are you able to
hut-2
if it feels like a criticism of you are
you able to handle that because a lot of
the time we're not able to handle
criticisms like on both on both sides so
this catch-22 is what a lot of men are
feeling and the culture right now is
speak up oh but not like that
yeah and then of course now we have the
benefit of hindsight about a year later
to see did that ad make you let money or
did it lose the money and it's complex
because Gillette's been losing quite a
lot of money for for many years because
of people like you with beards who
aren't buying razors anymore but
certainly what seems very clear is that
the ad didn't raise their sales which is
what an ad is supposed to do and it
didn't have a good impact on their on
the the metrics that determine how much
goodwill people have towards a brand
they've also stopped doing that kind of
campaign law in different territories
and then they also and this is a
statistic that needs to be taken with a
grain of salt they had like an 8 billion
writedown of Gillette this year they've
lost a lot of money not all of that is
because of the ad they it's they saying
it's currency fluctuations and it's very
difficult to know you know I haven't
bought you late in the last year so I
don't know if my behavior is anything to
go by but today it has not been great
for them and then around the same time
we had our first unexpected hit of the
year with Heather hi in talking about
toxic femininity and I think it's worth
saying that she doesn't like either term
toxic masculinity or toxic femininity
but the idea of it and she wrote a piece
for Colette earlier on about this
that if there's a lot of talk in the
media about one and I think it's worth
saying that Heather doesn't like either
turn toxic masculinity or toxic
femininity but if there is a lot of talk
in the media about toxic masculinity
what is that about and what might be the
other side of that conversation I hate
both phrases toxic masculinity and toxic
femininity and you know the piece that I
wrote for Colette I think was called on
toxic femininity to to make the point
right up front you know before I got
into it and the piece that this that
this was going to be that conversation
or at least a very small part of it
actually there's there's a lot a lot
more to say about it which is that men
can go violent few of them do but it's
bad women are much less likely to go
physically violent or on average smaller
and not as strong of course we're Dyess
likely to have used physical violence as
our weapon right men are more likely to
have used physical violence as their
weapon when they went violent women are
much more likely to use wiles and
sexuality because especially for young
women that is where their power is and
young women have such vast power over
basically every other demographic at
least in American culture in in some
cultures you know in the Far East where
elders are respected more this is not
this is not going to be the same kind of
dynamic so at the end of January we
released glitch in the matrix to so
glitch in the matrix one was pretty much
the one of one of the first films that
we released on the channel bleach and
the matrix 2 was the origins of the
intellectual dark web so an extended
interview with Eric Weinstein about it's
mostly his philosophy and how the
intellectual dark web was the the fruit
of a lot of patterns he's been tracking
since the 1980s and he talks about a lot
of really useful concepts in there like
kayfabe the gated institutional
narrative and I think it's a really I
was really impressed with with that
tried to kind of turn it into an
interesting documentary with a few
graphics and a bit sort of shifting it
around to make the context
clear part of me wants to work quietly
and part of me realizes that we have to
work in some public facing capacity and
I personally have found it much more
comfortable to have the private life to
not have everything that I'm thinking
broadcast to a large audience but I
think we've run out of time and so I
think some of us are somewhat
reluctantly choosing to make a different
call now I think that with the current
administration and the White House
you're seeing a real discontinuity with
the past and it wasn't the discontinuity
that I was hoping for we had to break
with the past and I think that the way
in which we are now breaking with the
past is so destructive nobody knows what
to believe nobody quite knows what's
true nobody knows where to turn this is
not a tenable situation and so either
we're going to descend into some kind of
permanent chaos or there is going to be
have to be something that we reboot from
and that thing cannot be simply left or
simply right and that's one of the
reasons the IDW is hopeful to me why the
IDW has been interesting to us since the
beginning is this in it certainly
initially and if you're interested I did
a talk recently at university in America
about the IDW called
my journey with the IDW where I went
into a little bit more but this sense at
the beginning of an emergent
conversation it was sort of the
intellectual dark web was the naming of
I mean a little bit of background if
you're not aware of the intellectual
dialogue at all it's the unofficial name
for a set of podcasters alternative
media personalities including Eric Joe
Rogan Dave Rubin Sam Harris Jordan
Peterson and it's a very and it named a
kind of emergent phenomenon the name
stuck so the name obviously there was
something behind that that could be
named and we've kind of digressed quite
a lot about what that particular thing
is that that's being named what is the
emergent phenomenon but but the next
surely at least there was this sense of
conversations that were alive and
potentially going somewhere new and
often resolving some of the really big
issues and/or potentially resolving some
of the bigger issues in society and
culture and I know that both Brett and
Eric for example see it as a much bigger
project than just the media and the IDW
is the media facing arm of a wider
conversation that needs to be had in
many different fields that have all
become stuck at the same time and that's
still that's still an important project
whether the the center of gravity is
still around the intellectual dark where
that particular constellation is an open
question and it's one that yeah I go
into a little bit in that talk and that
brings us really nicely into the next
big film that were going to talk about
and that was the interview with Ken
Wilber so Ken Wilber actually got in
touch with us after reading an article
that we wrote together about the
intellectual dark web where we called
the intellectual dark web and integral
an emergent integral conversation or
potentially an integral conversation so
if you're not familiar with the integral
terminology that's one of the problems
with it is that it gets lost in
terminology along the time the idea of
an integral at least of the spiral
dynamics part of integral theory is that
there are different value systems online
at the same time integral Theory
represents this development as a spiral
in this film will mostly be talking
about amber tribalism ethnocentric
authoritarian which first emerged about
5000 years ago
orange modern values the rational self
that emerged 300 years ago with the
liberal democracies and the beginning of
universal values Green the values of
relativism multiple perspectives
dialogue and consensus human rights
sometimes called postmodern which
emerged fully in the 1960s if they're
healthfully integrated they support each
other but each of them can believe that
their way of looking at the world is the
only true way and then they are mutually
exclusive for Wilbur the incomprehension
between these worldviews is what's
causing many of the worst excesses of
the culture wars
above these levels Wilbur says is
another level called integral or
second-tier from this perspective it's
clear that each of the previous ways of
seeing the world has value and needs to
be integrated what we're looking at
right now and one of the reasons I think
that the intellectual dark web has
particularly arisen at this time is that
we really did have the emergence of this
new stage of development and it really
is radically relativistic radically
egalitarian prison great deal of
emphasis on equal outcome and she's any
differences at all as the product of
oppression or discrimination and that's
where so many of the intellectual dark
web people are fighting against the same
look it's it's possible that some of
that is oppression no doubt but there
are so other reasons that we see these
differences and they might have to do
with different interests in male and
female for example nobody is holding
that as a absolutist ik view but it's a
view that they're not going to rule out
and you start to see this in a enormous
number of important areas in terms of
just how man on average and women on
average have different types of
interests in just what they find
interesting there's no evidence they
have different capacities it's not that
manner
cognitively smarter than women or
anything like that it's just they have
different things that they consider
important in life and they tend to
pursue those and part of the problem
that hasn't been answered well with the
green far-left
feminists is ok which is how do we
handle that and so naming the
intellectual dark web as an integral
phenomenon also
kind of I hope started to bring ken
wilber an integral into the conversation
because I think the IDW the intellectual
dart web desperately needs that
perspective because what can happen too
often with the IDW is that it can slip
into a low resolution narrative and it
initially constellated around a response
to the excesses of post-modernism which
is a really useful thing a necessary
thing but it has to move beyond there
and too often I think we see some of the
key figures in the intellectual dart web
just falling back into that kind of
oppositional space rather than looking
at what is the potential synthesis on
the other side of the culture war
dynamic yeah I think it's worth noting
as well I mean it integrals been a very
useful map and when we use on the
channel it's not the only map we use but
it is it's very useful for understanding
I think what's at play in the culture
and in fact a book Ken Wilber wrote
called Trump in the post truth world was
one of the things that really started
spurring our thoughts very early on it
revel wisdom around okay why are we
seeing these major shifts in culture and
why are we seeing these these tribal
dynamics playing out in a very big way
so it's hugely useful as that model and
then to the point you made before as
well part of integral is a yes and to
each stage as we develop and there's
lots of developmental models you know
Robert Keegan has one and there's many
different at play and they're all very
useful to see how adults develop how we
develop as adults rather than just as
children and how we continue to change
and grow part of that is saying yes and
to each stage so when you're eight years
old you don't reject everything you were
when you were five it's it's part of you
and you then transcend it so it's
transcend and include and that's also
been a process I think for me personally
this year is starting with real allergy
to green and postmodern values and a
real kind of rejection to more of a yes
n and going yeah I don't like the way
it's playing out in the culture for sure
I think it's very damaging however not
throwing the baby out with the bathwater
and looking at what does need to be
taken from that and then moved to
another more nuanced and more inclusive
and wide-ranging stage moving on perhaps
to the next piece we're going to talk
about which is Jaime Weil who was part
of integral the integral Institute for
quite a long
and as a deep familiarity was actually
teaching the integral map in business
for quite a long time he had a brilliant
line in that piece about that the
integral map is a is a really useful
operating system and that many of the
people who he calls breaking trail so
that the sort of the people who are sort
of at the cutting edge of the the
cultural conversation have that integral
map and I think that's a beautiful way
I've used that several times since that
the integral OS operating system is
really really useful the danger and
Jamie goes into this in the in the piece
is that you mistake the map for the
territory just kind of ironic because in
an integral they they say you definitely
need to avoid mistake in the map for the
territory but you see that so often
partly because it's a really powerful
and useful map because suddenly if
you're starting to talk about green
orange red and all of this very useful
terminology you can very easily just
start becoming very very insular and it
just becomes this conversation between
just inside baseball almost inevitably
and you see that so much about the
integral communities is this sort of
sense of turning in on itself and that's
that's really unfortunate it seems to be
the case as we move into these you know
nominally transpersonal communities is
that all of these thought leaders who
have been breaking trail right there but
they brought they brought through
something profound something unique
something useful they're bringing a tool
to our shared collective and by default
and or by design we're all wounded
healers we all need the thing that we've
built more than anybody else needs it
and I think that that same case is
probably true for Ken and rather than
having the people who have experienced
and benefited from integral theory then
rise up in some sort of unreconciled
slay the father angry child dynamic can
there be instead the sense of hey why
your life's work has lit things up in
me has helped guide my path Wright has
brought me to places I never had
imagined and perhaps can we then turn
around and give back the wounded healer
the realized gift that they offered in
the first place and not needs to not no
need to knock them down off pedestals
and no need to kind of reclaim our gold
and kind of Angry and dysfunctional ways
but to say thank you so much and let us
return the favor let us return academic
acknowledgement let us return community
let us return love appreciation
affection and challenge let us show up
as the humans you've been writing about
all along and let's help you take that
final step for yourself we don't all
need all of our teachers to be Moses
leading people to the promised land and
getting stuck on the edge we can
actually welcome the folks that help
guide us to that land - to the potty
itself just add to that another danger I
think of confusing a map when the
territory is that even if the map says
as integral often does practice is
important embodying the audience in your
life is important you have to make the
time to meditate you have to make the
time to do whatever else people can even
avoid that and not do the practice and
so that's something I've heard a lot of
people mention about not just integral
but lots of different let's say models
of reality you know is that people take
the model in place of actually having to
do the hard work of bringing it into
your life challenging yourself and
that's quite close to my heart because
we talk a lot on the channel about what
are the practices we need to do in order
to start living these ideas out in our
lives and having an imp have an impact
on ourselves and our communities and on
that note I wanted to introduce the next
person we're going to talk about who is
John Verve a key so John Verve a key
sort of hit the scene I suppose last
year he's a cognitive scientist at the
University of Toronto and he released a
youtube series called awakening from the
meaning crisis and that is quite a
hugely impressive series where he begins
I don't say prehistory and looking at
shamanism and looking at flow States and
goes all the way through the history of
Western philosophy from a cognitive
science angle to
cat why is there a crisis and meaning in
the culture what do we need to know
about what he would describe is the
grammar of our thought and where do you
psycho technologies as he refers them so
the practices I was just talking about
where do those fit into the mix and and
where do they come from why do we do
them in the first place and so he's
created a really brilliant narrative and
understanding of why are we where we are
which is obviously one of the key
questions we have a tribal wisdom is
what are the underlying dynamics between
behind the crisis and meaning and then
crucially what can we do about that yeah
and I think for me one of the real tests
of someone's thought is how often I find
myself using their terms or their
language when trying to explain things
like how useful of their conceptual
frameworks and John definitely I think
all of us would would say that we we've
used a lot of his language a lot the
idea of psycho technologies for example
is a really useful concept when we're
talking about kind of evolution and
mimetic evolution for example I'm trying
to salvage what I can from these axial
age wisdom traditions these systematic
sets of psycho technologies for
transforming you know consciousness
cognition character and community like
those are powerful we have to salvage
those and my reason for saying that is
because they they they were born from in
our meshed in the axial revolution and
it's in its two world mythology and all
kinds of ways of trying to give us a
grammar for thinking about self
transcendence that do not mesh well do
not fit well with the scientific
worldview so try and not get the wrong
connotations from this word but I am
trying to salvage from those wisdom
traditions right what we can't what we
know and can learn about this
meaning-making process and more
especially and importantly how to
engineer and create systemic sets of
psycho technologies that afford the
transformation and the transcendence
that people are longing for that's
what's very important and there's one
clip that I'm gonna play as well from
further something we did later on we
have a conversation with Jordan green
hall and they talked about a meta psycho
technology the solution that we've
developed as humans boost by the way is
in fact why we are where we are right II
goddess the psycho technology the
invention of psycho technology is a the
gift that keeps on giving and it moves
us further and further away from the
context that gave rise to it in the
first place second technology puts us on
a very different Fitness landscape very
dose instead of characteristic dynamics
and so we have to actually formulate the
psycho tech the meta psycho technology
of engaging in the design of psycho
technology that are in fact responsive
to the reality that we are finding
ourselves in and that is a very good way
for them oh I really liked that that was
really that really saying to me the
ladies put that I really liked about a
lot I really resonated with me that was
very clear that was those very
insightful that drew it all together
very nicely so it is is that oh yeah
that that's very interesting a very cool
putting how would you summarize that
John was that that we need to we need to
mindfully or create our own psycho
technologies to get through that that's
that the key well but the key piece I
got out of that is we need to step back
and create a meta psycho technology for
evaluating how we're designing our our
our psycho technologies and this is
analogous to in problem solving how you
have to you have to step back and have
meta Kuras --tx that look at how you are
creating and selecting the heuristics
you're going to use I have to say I'm
not entirely sure whether I understand
yet I kind of get it but I know that
that particular conversation that kind
of moment of emergence in that
conversation between Jordan and and John
was a real sense of are there's
something there and I know that that
kind of revelation has really informed
John bhave keys work since and he is now
putting together a new series called
after Socrates about the evolution of
dialectic about the evolution of sort of
interest
of truth as a practice which he says
that was intrinsic to the the ancient
Greeks they had they had that as part of
their culture it wasn't just the ideas
it was the the process of coming to
truth and that is something that we've
lost because we now think of ideas just
as propositional nodders and
interrelatedness between us and so
there's a there's a film coming out
maybe before this maybe slightly after
us but certainly over the Christmas
period where I interview him about that
and he talks about the the new series
that he's got coming up after Socrates
which he should definitely check out
then we had a whole series of films with
the evolutionary psychologists Diana
Fleischman and Jeffrey Miller including
one about their relationship about
polyamory and as Jeffrey predicted there
was a lot of response in the comments
you know it was said by a lot of folks
in the hall right politics is downstream
of culture but culture also apparently
is down the stream of the mating system
so if you really want to get people
riled up you challenge the mating system
that actually dominates you know
relations between the sexes but also
family structure and has knock-on
effects on everything from kind of the
design of housing and urban spaces to
the design of careers and the extent to
which people can kind of use freedom of
association to form little families or
poly tools or communes or whatever and
as soon as you kind of shake the tree of
monogamy and challenge that people panic
and they think like what else might have
to change if this is ever questioned we
actually don't really pay that much
attention to other polyamorous people
because we think that a lot of what
other polyamorous people endorse is
actively not to be yeah unless we put
too fine a point on it but yeah we I
mean I always like to say that we don't
endorse it we just talk about how it can
work for some people and about how it is
potentially you know the better way to
have a fuller life for people who can
manage jealousy and who you know I think
I actually don't understand how people
do polyamory
without an evolutionary perspective for
example and that is something that we're
planning on exploring more and writing
and videos yeah now we come to May and
the interview with Dave Rubin and I've
been kind of potentially wanting to do
an interview with him for a while he was
hugely important in the kind of as he as
he describes the connective tissue of
the intellectual dark web in the early
stages and I think if that interview had
happened a year before it would have
been a very different kind of interview
but in the run-up to it I I was sort of
researching reading and looking at a lot
of stuff and I I felt there were some as
a journalist I felt that there were some
questions that I had to ask him about
his interview technique about the way he
frames as interviews that I felt were
really important to ask I felt I
wouldn't have been able to kind of look
at myself in the mirror if I hadn't had
that opportunity which was similar with
with Ken Wilber to be honest there were
a couple of questions I asked at the end
- Ken Wilber about the impact of
integral and his relationship with
Andrew Cohen that I also felt needed to
be addressed if I'm going to have an
interview with Kem Wenger I need to
address those and it's not I I don't
enjoy that part of the job so much I
don't enjoy the sort of combative
interviews and there's also a danger of
being accused of sort of gotcha
journalism and all of those sort of
things which I think we're rightly tired
of in all of the mainstream media but
also as a journalist you have an
obligation you're in the place I mean
that the sort of the moral rules that
I've kind of internalized that
effectively you're in the place of many
other people who might want to have that
conversation so all of the the
conversation the discussions that are
out there are the questions that are out
there that you think have valid
questions you have some kind of
obligation to put them to that person
and there's a lot of controversy around
Dave Rubin some of which I think is
unfair some which I think is fair and so
I put those questions to him yeah well I
guess if there's a physical center of
the intellectual dark web it's right
here I mean it's in my garage so it's
not like you get you sit down with
someone and automatically you strengthen
them there's no automatic maybe they'll
be strengthened if their ideas are good
and man
I don't think I'd ever argue that you
shouldn't sit down with someone I think
my main point is whether people are
being challenged enough because and that
goes back to my point before about has
has it shifted because because now there
are expectations I mean we're seeing
that for Joe Rogan I think we're seeing
this with you as well that there are
expectations that you will hold people
to account in a way that when you're an
upstart kind of alternative media
chatter yes we're not there right so as
I said earlier they look the bigger you
get the more relevant you get the more
haters are gonna come out but the more
that legitimate criticism will come out
- and again I address this all the time
what do you think's the most legitimate
criticism it's not really for me to say
what the legitimate criticism of me if
someone wants to say that they don't
like the way I interview or that I don't
ask hard enough questions or something
like that
well I suppose that is a legitimate
criticism of me it's not the way I like
doing my business and you know if you
don't like what I'm doing then I would
say you don't have to watch doesn't mean
I'm doing it perfectly I'm doing I'm
doing something that I believe is good
apparently a lot of other people think
it's good too and and apparently it's
pretty rare these days and there was
some communication with Dave behind on
afterwards and then I watched it and I
watched it back and I and I think it's
one of the better interviews that I've
done I think I explained very clearly at
the beginning talk about the values of
the IDW intellectual dark web and then
and he agreed with most of those values
and then at the end I put some points to
him that I thought well where he haven't
lived up to those values I think it's an
impactful interview I think it's
important one I think it's a fair one
and also I think it's really important
for us as a channel that we maintain
that integrity and maintain that ability
to ask the harder questions as well as
the the easier questions yeah and I
think that also speaks to one of the
core I suppose values we have which is
truth orienting ourselves to truth as
best we can and I think that runs
through most of what we do or we hope it
does and so I think one of the big
experiences we had with that this year
was the rebel wisdom summit so we've
been doing smaller evening events where
we have a speaker and then get people
into smaller groups to
some of the techniques we used in our
weekend retreats to you know explore the
truth how do I feel about these ideas
what do I feel I can't say and just
slowly feeling into that so the summit
was an experiment to see could we do
that on a bigger scale so we had 150
people we had Brett Weinstein
Heather huiying Iain McGilchrist and
Jordan Hall and as well as them talking
and kind of modeling that on stage we
also broke off into smaller groups so
that has been a big process of can we
bring truth into the cultural
conversation because very often I think
many of us feel stifled we feel we don't
know how to really tackle these hugely
complex ideas that are hot topics in the
culture whether it's something like
brexit or immigration or whether it's
gender dynamics in the culture there's
so many zones that feel like they're
no-go zones their mind their mine feels
conversational minefields but that's
very much I think there's a huge need
for the tech kind of techniques one
might use in in an you know personal
growth workshop which is driven by truth
so what is the truth of what I'm feeling
right now and you know there's
techniques like circling which we'll
talk about later that we've we've looked
at this year as well which really focus
on the inter subjective truth and that's
been a huge theme so the summit was an
experiment in that and we learned a lot
from it and now we're gonna be expanding
that at the rebel ism festival next May
so about a year later the summit was a
really enjoyable event and I think one
of the big learnings that were taking
into the festival is rather than try and
curate a whole event where everyone goes
through the same experience it's to give
people the option to dive into different
things and create multiple tracks so you
can actually go way deeper if you want
to like into a into a circling session
or even a breathwork session or you can
go to the the talks and you can you can
do tasters of other things like having
that variety of different options or how
choose-your-own-adventure
I think is something that we've we've
realized will paradoxically allow people
to create their own experience and
potentially have a much deeper
experience and that will benefit
everyone I think so now in June
something that surprised what a lot of
people was John Cleese so just a bit of
the back
story on that really quite fascinating
because I first saw John Cleese's name
on a book by Richard Thomas so rich
Thomas has been on the channel before
I'm a huge admirer of his work
especially passion of the Western mind
which highly recommend as a kind of
grand narrative of where we are in
Western cultures it's quite astonishing
and john cleese there's a quote from
john cleese saying something like one of
the one of the best oversights of
western culture I've ever read like okay
that's so John is obviously because
there's a real spiritual or mythopoetic
core to Richard Thomas's works as I hope
to john cleese obviously has a kind of
spiritual side that I wasn't aware of
and then we also found out that he's
connected to Iain McGilchrist who also
has been on the channel was at summit
and that he was going to be over for a
workshop and got in touch with him and
he's a big fan of Ian's work so agreed
to do an interview on the channel and we
had a quite a short period of time just
to grab him in between sort of sessions
on the on the course but it was really
nice to see that different side of his
personality I've always been interested
in stuff to do with psychology of almost
every time and I'm also interested in
spiritual stuff in a very weakened form
which is what I what I call why we're
here is there a purpose of life and of
course the current scientific paradigms
has no purpose at all consciousness is
an epiphenomenon caused by chemical so
chemical reaction which i think is
complete nonsense it reminds me of what
George Orwell once said which was only
an intellectual could believe that
so August we released the science and
psychology of polarization series so for
films including a kind of main film to
link it all together I was really really
pleased with that because that had been
in the in the can for quite a while we'd
interviewed Stephen Porges a while ago
interviewed Peter Levine in America two
of the kind of the most interesting
thinkers around the body around trauma
around communication around
defensiveness and openness and all of
that dynamic but and to bring that
together with the sort of cultural piece
and the difficult conversations piece
felt very right and complete that felt
very cutting edge and still feels very
cutting edge and seeing people at Alex
Evans were working in this area with the
collective psychology project trying to
get and more psychologically informed
model into government and
decision-making this feels like
something that's really important and I
was very pleased about the way that it
was received and also it seemed to sort
of reach a new audience of people who
were kind of interested and and felt
like we were zeroing in on okay what we
really need to be talking about is how
do we have these conversations at all
like what are the things that are
preventing us having them why are they
why are they collapsing and it becomes
quite an interim portent dynamic of okay
how do we what's Ground Zero Ground Zero
is learning these skills without a doubt
is learning our psychology and the one
key piece which I kind of will repeat
again and again and again it's like if
we're starting to feel defensive can we
make that leap to feeling curious about
that defensiveness and open to what what
we're trying to be told by that
experience if you're talking to two
people who are in the hyper-vigilant
State the sympathetic adrenal state or
the shut down state even more so you
can't engage with them because you
perceive them either as threat or as
mortal threat because your nervous
system is stuck in that groove and so
there's no way you can really listen to
another person and and express yourself
so they want to listen to you while
you're in one of these stuck States you
have to be able to come into the social
engagement system scientists Steven
Porges came up with a revolutionary
theory that links together psychology
neuroscience and evolutionary biology it
was called polyvagal and focused on the
vagus the longest nerve in the body that
links together all the major organs and
also connects to the face and voice
for the first time there was a theory
that explained how our own body and mind
are intimately connected to our facial
expressions voice and social engagement
system and therefore to others how the
vagus nerve moderate sixes of trust and
safety how we're curious and open to new
information and experiences and how if
we're not feeling safe then we fall into
defensiveness we start to see everything
unfamiliar as a threat they're unable to
take in new information we are connected
species and if we don't appreciate that
we are is as injuring the species and we
have to take on a responsibility the
bottom line is I think there are gonna
be more and more people having this
understanding because now you have with
polyvagal theory and neurobiology that
supports the philosophy LOF achill and
for many people even a spiritual
religious fear so you have a convergence
of different orientations all ending up
in the same point one of the ways that
we know that it's being kind of
influential cultural is that we've been
invited now a couple of times to give it
as a talk yes we created a talk called
the neuroscience of difficult
conversations and the first one we did
was a wilderness festival and the
turnout was way bigger than we expected
which was really encouraging and it
really seems to be something that feels
needed in the culture right now is to
understand what are the biological
dynamics of difficult conversations
because I think we all have that lived
experience of falling into defensiveness
or feeling that when someone attacks an
idea we're being attacked and then it
just goes downhill whether it's in a
relationship or whether it's in a
political discussion over the dinner
table I think it filled in a missing
piece and our thinking as well and was
was incredibly valuable to understand
polyvagal theory to understand the yeah
the science and psychology of what what
happens in a conversation and so
delivering that talk was really fun as
well because we also brought in Jonathon
Heights work around the value systems
that we're bringing probably the only
talk where we get to talk about a man
having sex with a chicken legitimately
and if anyone's read Jonathan Hyde's
work you'll probably know what that's
about and then also just having some fun
practice around okay where I think we
it started to talk with when's the last
does anyone remember the last time they
had an argument and everyone raised
their hand it's like and was everyone
you know put your hand down if you were
wrong in that argument it's all the hand
stay up which is that's part of heights
inside is that's how we all feel and so
in order to start understanding and I'm
picking it it's not just about
understanding the dynamics of having a
good faith conversation like is it was a
big factor of the IDW that's crucial and
that's really important but there's no
sense or there's no realistically we're
not going to have a good faith
conversation unless we're also aware of
these biological dynamics of what
happens when we meet each other in that
way it's just it's not going to work we
need to have that fuller understanding
of what's happening yes we had two of
our biggest series or biggest releases
in August the second one being a
collective intelligence series and
neither of the neither of them had like
huge views compared to some of the
things on the channel but in terms of
impacts and the the conversations that
we've been having since and also the
among the members and the kind of
conversations we're having with our
subscribers and our members we know they
were really really impactful it was
something that was really alive for them
and really sort of named something that
a lot of people were very interested in
and the collective intelligence series
links very well to the the polarization
piece because you can't enter into this
sort of generative dialogue collective
intelligence coherence emergence unless
you're able to really know you're know
yourself to be sort of we've talked
about the phrase sovereignty but to be
able to to not be sort of hijacked by
our limbic system hijacked by our kind
of reactions to things or just go into a
track of knowing that we're right and
then just delivering some kind of
pre-prepared speech those are all the
things that sort of block genuine
emergent dialogue so there's a there's a
really interesting link between them it
also ties back to the original
attraction to the intellectual dark web
of that sense of a conversation that
could go anywhere and it's not just into
sort of reactive spaces of a narrative
that we're already familiar with and
we'd argue that that hasn't necessarily
been sustained by the intellectual dark
web but we are going to have to find
some way of doing that because we're not
going to be able to get
the cultural cul-de-sacs we've created
for ourselves unless we can have these
generative conversations which also
includes kind of what are the things
that are derailed in those conversations
well the perspectives one of the
attitudes that are derail in those
conversations but the what was really
striking about the collective
intelligence series is we had a
beautiful piece in the center of that
with three of the the most interesting
and impressive thinkers we've
interviewed since we started doing the
channel Jamie will Jordan green hall and
Daniel SHM Acton Berger we just so
happened they just so happened to be in
the same place in in America while we
were over there and got this emergent
two-and-a-half-hour sort of emergent
sprawling conversation that went from
the sort of sublime to the impenetrable
coherence is this ephemeral emergent
property best never named the never
subject to reality captured reality
tunnel capture like if that thing then
how the hell do scale it because we're
storytelling monkeys and at some point
we need recipes to help the thing
propagate so this could list everybody's
generators then why does it always break
down mm-hmm why don't why every time you
try to scale to break down one of the
reasons is because as our friend Lao Tzu
discovered and by the way also a friend
Buddha discovered and her friend Jesus
discovered every time the storytelling
monkeys try to turn to a story to tell
they fuck it up so let's be mindful of
that and recognize that the storytelling
piece of it definitely isn't the answer
okay so Sherlock Holmes style now carve
that out of the available portfolio of
things that we can do how do we go about
doing anything at all that doesn't
involve being a storytelling monkey oK
we've got it we've got an arrow problem
it's smaller it's a smaller space what
do you know so let's just think I mean
if you know where we are culturally
these days there's a lot of people are
stumbling into these spaces via broad
access to ecstatic technologies so
whether that's transformational ffedith
festivals or you know transformational
technologies or whatever it is or
psychopharmacology you know all these
things people are bumbling into these
spaces on purpose or
they're getting there they're
recognizing holy shit we're in the deep
end and or this is rad this is awesome
this is terrifying this is powerful
right whatever it will be they they're
they know it when they're getting there
even if they're not a hundred isn't sure
of how they got there and then the
moment they're no longer in that
coherent field we're back to trying to
make sense of it in the prison-house of
language telling stories and making
analogies or metaphors so let's look at
extinction I think we this distinction I
think is quite helpful there's at least
two distinct uses of language this one
over here
I'll call semantic reality mapping this
is really good for things like building
houses or putting together battle plans
it Orient's coordinated behavior where
the checksum of reality is pretty strong
science does a lot of that science is
pretty much this kind of thing over here
is poetry parable where the fingers
pointing to the moon and the point is
the moon not the finger this we can use
which is to be very careful that we're
not doing this so the problem that I
think happens all the time
particular with the folks that wear lots
of feathers and like to take too many
drugs is they do this so they have an
experience and then try to turn to
science so prescriptive versus
descriptive
both really they do prescription and
descriptions because poetry is not
really description
it's an octave figurative versus literal
yes yeah so the trick is we have to
actually be able to use language as some
way of creating a a resonance frequency
or protocol match that generates a
capacity for communication that is not
itself specifically semantic which I
would propose both parable and poetry do
it Orient's you in the direction of a
feeling in yourself like thinking about
poetry when you read a poem you don't
understand
the poem but something about the way
that the poem coordinates language helps
you weren't in yourself to an experience
that feels like the feeling that the
poet was also feeling and so it creates
a possibility of there being a
connection at the level of interior
feeling not a connection at the level of
understanding
well sometimes something you're on I
mean it felt like you did have some
future-forward practicality and
application in your initial description
you said it does well with novelty and
it's anti fragile and there's me as you
thought of it feel like timeless
qualities but it for sure feels
important now then going forward and and
I was wondering because if we can't do
the here's the instructions on how to
get back here because then we've named a
thing that's not the thing and emergent
coherence is kind of this weird slippery
thing to pin down you have communities
of practice like Quakers and others that
have spent centuries and even you know
generations passing on that knowledge I
was just with some indigenous for DNA
and Lakota folks right and they have an
infinite tradition of we will talk until
the thing that needed to get done
emerges but nor are we on the clock
and if this takes 10 minutes so BIA if
this takes 10 days so be it so is there
a version of this that is you know kind
of quote-unquote scalable in the 21st
century there are moments of real beauty
and real kind of emergent quality of
just old beautiful analogy beautiful
beautiful comparison almost like this
poetic lots of live poetic experience
just on that point around drifting in
and out of coherence I think
something that for me was the big
learning of this whole exploration we
did or are doing let's say around
collective intelligence because we also
ran a collective intelligence lab where
we had three weekly sessions and we got
about we only have space for about 20
odd people and we got a b-plus
kind of let's say people interested in
we ran it at cost so it was really just
about seeing if we could get an
interestingly diverse group of people
together to start practicing some of
these things and really what we learned
a lot and we made probably a lot of
mistakes as well but it was very
enjoyable as a process one of the things
that has come out of me is that point
about drifting in and out of coherence
because that was the big takeaways that
coherence doesn't mean sameness and it
also doesn't mean we're all agreeing all
the time and there's a big I think
that's a huge interesting thing to parse
out it's not a problem for us to
disagree and there's no there's a phrase
that I heard from a guy called Greg
Thomas recently who I spoke to is a jazz
expert called antagonistic cooperation
you'll get that in a jazz where you know
a jazz kind of riff and that's a
metaphor they use actually in the making
sense of sense making conversation
there's someone comes in with a trumpet
and then someone fights back with a you
know saxophone but they're working
towards a similar container so it's
still about cooperation but there's you
know there's conflict is okay and part
of coherence is coming in and out of it
and that's something we did in the lab
you know we we established some
coherence and then put in a question
that was punchy we're you know some some
of them might have been you know one of
them was just brexit good or bad and we
had people stand at other sides of the
room or would you rather have a male or
female boss people standing over to the
room you know and they almost always
split people almost in two which was
great and then we brought those into
conversation and almost inevitably those
are the kinds of questions that bring us
out of coherence because they really
activate something in us and it's
difficult to maintain it but part of the
process seems to be and a lot of people
we've spoken to have mentioned this so
Dinah Shore Hamilton has been on the
channel recently and Bonita Roy as well
that that is part of the process and for
me that was a lesson because it's kind
of just keep we can't just be in
coherence all the time because we don't
get that creative energy and that that
juice that comes from polarity
and so just finally on that I think that
applies to the wider cultural
conversation that I think we've been
covering is that you know trying to find
a way beyond tribal ization and
polarization doesn't mean trying to find
some place where we're all thinking the
same thing it just means that we can
actually have the conversation because
when we're in fight flight or freeze and
you know this this goes back to the
science and psychology of polarization
series we can't talk about anything we
can't have that
generative dialogue so we can still
disagree but it's about whether we're
shut down whether were frozen whether
we're trying to fight or run away and
that's a real nuance between those two
things and that's like a that's a
continuous I think exploration of how do
we get that that balance right so that
within a conversation any of us can feel
into okay am i pushing back because I
really feel this is an important point
or am I feeling threatened that I'm
attacking there's so much to it and so
so many of the people we've talked to
you know who've been doing it a lot
longer than us have come to December
similar conclusions around that around
the complexity of it and also how much
we can get out of a practice like this
around you know collective intelligence
and generative conversation you make a
really important point there I think
it's worth highlighting and repeating
cuz I see a lot of confusion in this
space and these kind of conversations
around coherence and it's a point that
Jamie wheel made to me the other day and
hopefully we'll get a chance to kind of
do a recording around it at some point
is you can't get to coherence by trying
for coherence you can't wish your way
into let's let's just let's just be in
coherence right now you get to coherence
through doing the hard thing you get to
coherence through go through going into
the difficult conversations raising
whatever's in the field and hopefully
working through it with no guarantee
that that's going to happen but this
coherence is the space on the other side
of doing the hard things and that just
has to it doesn't come from anywhere
else and that was the other learning
from putting on the collective
intelligence lab was we realized it was
very ambitious to try and create kind of
coherence in a group of say 20 strangers
actually I think we got to some level of
coherence even with that because we were
very lucky to have a very skilled
circling facilitator John Thompson of
circling Europe who was helping us and
was incredibly good at his what he did
and
in a really beautiful space but what I
found we did manage was the five the
sewer who were putting it on because we
were having discussions about how we're
going to run the the workshop and all of
this stuff was coming up we had sort of
arguments discussions very clearly what
I found is we got to some level of
emergence and coherence in the teaching
team with a shared goal with something
that we were actually kind of moving
towards with the kind of dedication and
ground rules that we will raise whatever
comes up between us we will say what
we're feeling we'll make sure that that
everything is expressed then you can
start moving towards coherence you can't
get there through let's try and be in
coherence right now yeah absolutely and
that's something we've seen on our men's
retreats as well it's it's the trials
and tribulations of the hero's journey
that that creates that trust and that
unity between us and there's no and
there's no short cutting map yeah and
the collective intelligence series is
definitely one that we're going to
return to quite a few times and we
followed up with a really good interview
with Bonita Roy who drew out some really
important distinctions between
collective intelligence and what she
calls collective insight practice
collective insight practice is a
methodology for people to get together
and together come up with insights
knowings plans mental models ideas that
neither any of them had when they answer
together and it's not just some kind of
mash-up of clips that people had it's
something that affects people or seems
to people as entirely novel and new and
they know they couldn't have come up
with that without the participation of
other people they know even the crazy
nonlinear streams that they went off
with someone in an argument or a wacky
humorous thing all these somehow played
a part and either disrupting the system
we're moving the
you're creating new pathways for
thinking in that everyone has held a
piece for this new paradigm shift or
this new way of perceiving or new idea
or new approach to have arisen so now
we're in August and the war on
sense-making piece with Daniel Schmidt
hamburger which did surprisingly well
like I it was a great piece and I
thought it would do well but I was
thinking sort of twenty thirty thousand
something like that and then it just
sort of kept going up and really caught
caught the zeitgeist I think there's
something very I mean he he laid it out
beautifully it's sort of a long one and
a half hour an analysis of the
sense-making landscape the information
ecology and why it's polluted which has
been really really interesting to think
about and to develop our own thoughts
around these sort of ideas including
sort of the idea of like ruler maker and
how how why is the information landscape
so polluted and what do we do about kind
of making it less polluted like to just
get a sense of why like how big a deal
this is you take any of the biggest
issues in the world like the issues that
could determine whether or not we keep
existing as a species okay so take big
environmental issues like climate change
is there is disagreement as to whether
climate change is relieved in a thing
and to the extent that it is a thing
what the causes are and what the time
skills are now most people who believe
fervently know climate change is real
97% of climate scientists agree it's
anthropogenic greenhouse gases etc most
of the people that believe that
fervently enough to kind of like go into
narrative warfare for it have never
actually looked at the primary data
deeply themselves and yet there's an
almost religious fervor around it that
was based on having proxied their sense
making the people who they believe so
do UN's headed or the Gates Foundation
set it or whatever it is I've heard it
repeated enough times just just through
repeatability like I have been
programmed to believe this thing is true
which is not that different than
believing a fundamentalist religion
religious ideal right and let's say we
take people's fervent ideas on vaccines
or their fervent ideas on the viability
of market ideology or almost anything
like that almost no one who has fervent
ideas has a good epistemic basis for the
level of certainty they hold there's a
decoupling between how much certainty
they have and how much certainty they
should have through right process and
then you look at who are they proxying
their sense making - in most the time
they're not even proxying their sense
making - the people who did the original
research many of whom disagree with each
other and were funded by somebody to say
something that is not fully true in the
first place and who maybe were employing
epistemic biases themselves but
typically it's somebody else who looked
at all of that and then someone else who
looked at all of that so you might have
like a bunch of climate scientists into
someone who is at speaking about that as
a client's climate scientists at a more
synthetic level like a james hansen or
whatever - then like a gor or someone
who is actually speaking to the public
who were proxying are sense-making - and
we say okay how many steps removed is it
and how good was the original data
and we had a lot less Jordan Peterson
this year compared to last but just
towards the end of the year I was in
Toronto and took the opportunity to do
an interview with Patricia Marco Chia
who directed the film the rise of Jordan
Peterson which had just come out and the
really interesting part of that story is
that she didn't expect to make the film
she ended up making she was really
interested in Jordan Peterson's
philosophy Jordan Peterson's opinions
about kind of religion and mythology and
that's what she wanted the film to be
about originally and then as she was
making it he released the professor
against political correctness videos and
then suddenly became kind of as we've
described the one-man lightning rod for
the culture war and then that story kind
of overtook her and that's the one she
ended up making one of the ideas that
led me to his book maps of meaning early
on was just from reading different
philosophers I sort of came to this
conclusion that you can have two people
in the same room you know in the same
place at the same coffee table in front
of them but your belief system and the
way you frame the world informs reality
to the extent where we can literally be
in two different realities even if we're
beside each other and this was like a
big aha moment for me of well we're kind
of screwed like how can people really
understand each other and resolve
conflicts and I remember that being the
initial thing that somehow led me I
think through some Google search to maps
of meaning so it's interesting how I you
know later found myself working on this
film about Jordan's comments on Bill c16
involving into all of this other these
other issues of political correctness
but with with this idea of culture war
looming underneath all of that so it's
been I guess an evolution of a lot of
different ideas and then just out in the
last few weeks is war on sense-making
too which obviously is a sequel to
Daniels piece where he talks a lot more
about the kind of weaponization of the
information ecology like how even true
things can be weaponized and how even
the information about how things a
weaponized can be weaponized and then
it's sort of kind of like a Hall of
Mirrors but it's really beautifully put
together and Daniel has a real
for making quite abstract complex ideas
intelligible to people we can see that
these types of patterns have happened in
the past and led to war and resets and I
think that that's too costly to happen
again and so outside of everyone
recognizing that and having that
motivate their willingness to do
something really uncomfortable which is
to be willing to disagree with the
in-group that they're part of even where
the in group will use ostracizing and
shaming as a way to hold them in line
and to really engage with other people
in perspectives and to not do the lazy
thing of just defecting to the sense
making that someone else that you hold
as legitimate Authority gave you but
really engaging earnestly with all of
the perspectives that you can to try to
understand what makes sense to then also
understand what a way forward that
doesn't look like war looks like I don't
think there are any good chances for the
world unless a lot of people start doing
that earnestness and sincerity empowered
by really deep courage and a deep kind
of epistemic humility is going to make
someone misfit for every in-group
currently which is the valley crossing
that people have to go through to
basically leave the forces that are
irate arrayed in a war that we're all
sides are wrong to hopefully have enough
people who do that that start to find
each other and don't do a new tribal
groupthink thing but all engage in
earnest actual thinking themselves an
actual conversation without orienting
towards groupthink that can start to
make a new strange attractor
so we're really pleased that we've got
him coming as one of our main speakers
for the rebel wisdom festival in May
next year so just time to talk about a
few of the films that are coming up at
the beginning of 2020 which I think
people will really enjoy because they're
taking on some of the inquiries that
we've been engaged in this year firstly
there's playing with a couple of
different titles for this potentially
it's war on sense-making 3 with Janie
Weil responding to some of the points
that Daniel made in war and sense-making
and it may be called warrants that's
making three and may be called the
infinite game because that sort of seems
like a more appropriate name for what
he's kind of sketching out and there's
also a piece called culture war 2.0 from
a new correspondent in Toronto Peter
Lindbergh and he if people have bring it
up and put the the link in the show
notes here he wrote a piece called
culture war 2.0 and coined a lot of
these really useful phrases like mimetic
mediation the gray pill and so we've put
it together with graphics an interview
that I did with him out in Toronto the
idea was an invitation to the reader to
look at it from a different perspective
and I view this this this whole hallway
paper in the mega tribes in the frame
that this is a multipolar almost
postmodern war is this sort of a
psychoactive drug because if you see the
mimetic tribe that you belong to
alongside all these other mimetic tribes
that might jog you out of your belief
system just for a moment I hope that
does really really well because I think
a lot of the terms and the framings and
the way that he looks at the cultural
landscape it's really really important
really really useful for us to kind of
play with going forward and and I think
will open up a new kind of Vista and
understanding about what we're doing
going forward into 2020 so you mentioned
the festival that's our next major event
that's happening at the end of May and
will be rather than one day like the
summit it's two days it's very much a
choose-your-own-adventure and really
looking forward to it but we have a
brilliant lineup of speakers and
facilitators as well
and as well as that we've got the online
course the very first rebel wisdom an
online course since making 101 which we
just launched and is selling really
quickly so there's plenty of information
around that we'll put in the show notes
if anyone's interested in that as well
so thank you very much for everyone
who subscribed watch to become a member
in 2019 it's been a really bracing
exciting year for us and we're looking
forward to seeing you in 2020 well done
for making it to the end I just wanted
to let you know a few things we've got
coming up including the biggest event
we've ever done the rebel wisdom
festival which will be a mix of ideas
and dialogues between people like
Douglas rushkoff Daniel SH maxim burger
Bonita Roy Rupert Sheldrake John vivace
and many more and because wisdom isn't
just intellectual it's also about
practice will be offering experiences
like circling different interpersonal
dialogue mindfulness breathwork
and many other with world-class
facilitators we're also running our
first online course called sense making
101 and if you're enjoying the content
you can help us make more by joining the
rebel wisdom club which will give you
discounts on the courses and the events
and also access to a load more content
on the website including all of our live
events it'll also give you access to our
growing community which is something we
want to make a real focus for 2020
adding more meetups and other services
for members so I hope you enjoyed the
film and see you soon
you